Big things come in small packages
Little Man is a comedy, crime film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans.
After leaving the prison, the dwarf criminal Calvin Sims joins to his moron brother Percy
to steal an expensive huge diamond in a jewelry for the mobster Walken.
They are chased by the police, and Calvin hides the stone in the purse of the
executive Vanessa Edwards, whose husband Darryl Edwards wants to have a baby.
Percy convinces Calvin to dress like a baby and be left in front of the
Edwards's house to get inside the house and retrieve the diamond.
Darryl and Vanessa keep Calvin for the weekend and decide to adopt him,
while Walken threatens Darryl to get the stone back.
Calvin, played by Marlon Wayans.
Darryl, played by Shawn Wayans.
Vanessa, played by Kerry Washington.
Pops, played by John Witherspoon.
Percy, played by Tracy Morgan.
Greg, played by Lochlyn Munro.
Little Man is a 2006 American crime comedy film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans, who co-wrote and
co-produced it with Marlon and Shawn Wayans, who both also star in lead roles.
The film co-stars Kerry Washington, John Witherspoon, Tracy Morgan,
Lochlyn Munro, Chazz Palminteri and Molly Shannon.
It follows a jewel thief with dwarfism who hides the proceeds of his latest
robbery, then pretends to be a very large baby in order to retrieve it.
Theatrically released in the United States on July 14, 2006, the film was a commercial
success, but was critically panned and won three Golden Raspberry Awards.
The film explores themes of baby, small person,
married couple, adoption, criminal.
The tone is lighthearted.